Kheel, Theodore W. Newspaper Clipping File 6017
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Theodore W. Kheel Newspaper Clipping File
1941-2002
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
6017
8 cubic feet
8 linear ft.
News clippings, records.
Subject files and chronologically arranged, bound clippings.
5758173
Biographical / Historical
Theodore Woodrow Kheel was said to be named for both Woodrow Wilson and his political rival Theodore Roosevelt, the result of a compromise between his politically differing parents. The settlement presaged a career in which Kheel would be tapped by mayors, governors, and presidents to settle disputes that were part of the nation's major political and social transitions from post-World War II to well into the 21st century.
Born in 1914 in Brooklyn, Ted Kheel attended public high school in the Bronx. He was awarded a Regents scholarship to Cornell University, where he attended an accelerated undergraduate law school program permitting him to earn a bachelor's and law degree in six years.
In private practice for a brief time after graduation from law school, Kheel soon was offered a position as a National Labor Relations Board attorney in Washington. Kheel's special talents as a mediator and his obvious political skills soon gave him the opportunity to move to a new war-time agency, where he was initially hired as principal mediation officer. By 1944, he had been appointed executive director of the National War Labor Board, with a staff of 2,500 who were hearing 150 disputes a week. Kheel's work at the WLB introduced him to the most important figures in the labor movement and key government officials' contacts he would use effectively in the future.
Following the end of World War II, Kheel returned to New York City and was drafted by Mayor O'Dywer to serve in the city's new Labor Relations Division, which Kheel came to head within a year. With the agreement of the mayor, Kheel was able to serve both in this position and maintain a separate, private law practice.
In 1949, Kheel was appointed to a part-time position as impartial chairman for an important segment of public transit in New York City, a position in which he would render 30,000 decisions through 1982. Also in 1949, Kheel became a partner in the New York law firm Battle, Fowler, Jaffin and Kheel. His skills in conflict resolution led an observer to remark that the firm's work began with a battle, ended by Kheel.
During his more than half a century of involvement in labor matters, Kheel was known above all else for his extraordinary ability to get feuding parties to make concessions to reach an agreement. In the important New York and national labor disputes which he would be called to mediate, Kheel's approach was to protect management rights and at the same time demand fairness to workers while also trying to protect the public interest in the issue.
Kheel's was frequently the voice of reason in settling a number of extremely difficult labor disputes of the 1960s and 1970s. Mayor Robert F. Wagner, Jr., turned to Kheel to help end the 114-day newspaper strike of 1962-63. Among his most infamous cases was the strike involving Mike Quill, head of the Transport Workers Union, who publically battled Mayor John V. Lindsay in 1965-66. Kheel's efforts also included helping coordinate bargainers and mediators during the 35-day New York City teachers' strike in 1968. President Lyndon B. Johnson summoned Kheel to Washington in 1964 to help mediate 10 days of feverish negotiations that prevented a nationwide rail walkout. Kheel would ultimately serve as a mediator and advisor for virtually every New York mayor from O'Dwyer to Beame, for the Kennedy-Johnson Administration, and other presidential administrations as well.
Kheel's interests in public issues were not limited to the labor sector. The policy disputes that came to his attention as a mediator and lawyer frequently cried out for larger solutions, and Kheel was not averse to using his considerable public presence and media contacts to seek redress, especially for what he viewed as past institutional injustices or misguided government actions. Although pressed to do so on a number of occasions, Kheel refused to run for elective office, preferring the role of a labor neutral and public advocate.
Kheel was also not averse to backing his powers of persuasion with legal action: a fierce advocate for public transit, he initiated a class action lawsuit over the Port Authority of New York and New Jersey's refusal to fund mass rail transit. His most sustained crusade for the public good related to his battle to limit commuter auto traffic and control highway building in New York City in favor of increased use of public transportation. Initially attacked by Port Authority officials and some city, state, and federal politicians of both parties, many of the solutions originally proposed by Kheel, including the concept of the subsidized fare, became public policy in later years.
An early supporter of the civil rights movement, Kheel and his wife Ann become involved with the New York Urban League in the 1950s. He served as its president in 1955 and as national president for four years. He worked with President Johnson on race issues and with Martin Luther King, Jr., in a libel suit against the New York Times. Kheel's mediation skills led to important strides in hiring African Americans in the airline industry. His reputation for sensitivity to minority issues resulted in his becoming involved in efforts to add civilians to the New York City Police Review Board in 1965. Kheel was also recruited as a peacemaker in the 1968 Ocean Hill-Brownsville Teachers dispute.
Even though Kheel handled disputes for transit workers, typesetters, and longshoremen, he reveled in the finer things in life, and dabbled as a restaurateur in fine food and was a patron of the fine arts.
He once owned a stake in Le Pavillon, a leading French restaurant in Manhattan, among others. He also represented numerous artists, including Robert Rauschenberg and Christo, and was the prime mover in the realization of the long-heralded Gates Project in Central Park in 2005.
He also made millions of dollars as an entrepreneur while facilitating sustainable economic and social change. He was the lead investor in the giant Punta Cana resort, transforming 30 miles of jungle in the Dominican Republic, and helped bring about the airport that opened that country to tourists and travelers.
Finding the solution to problems such as the impact of automation on the workplace, community disputes, and protecting a sustainable environment in which mankind will flourish, to name but a few, were the focus of Kheel's interest, enthusiasm, and financial support. He was the prime mover, bringing along like-minded citizens and specialists, in the creation of organizations to find solutions to the more intractable issues facing society. The Foundation on Employee Health, Medical Care and Welfare, the Foundation on Automation and Employment (and its British counterpart), Automation House, the Institute for Mediation and Conflict Resolution, and the Earth Pledge Foundation were among the most successful of such efforts. In the same vein, in collaboration with Price, Waterhouse in 1994, Kheel formed Prevention and Early Resolution of Conflicts, Inc. (PERC), now housed at Cornell ILR as Cornell/PERC Institute.
A prolific writer, Kheel is perhaps best known for his encyclopedic work on labor law. Throughout a career that was active almost until his death at age 96 in November 2010, he was able to balance, with amazing success, advocacy of the public good and the management of a successful law and mediation practice and other business and cultural interests.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives 227 Ives Hall Tower Road Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheelref@cornell.edu https://catherwood.library.cornell.edu/kheel/
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, February 27, 2008
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, October 30, 2015
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5024: Theodore W. Kheel Arbitration Awards 6021 AV: Theodore W. Kheel Audio-Visual Materials 6021: Theodore W. Kheel Records 6021 MB: Theodore W. Kheel Memorabilia 6021 P: Theodore W. Kheel Photographs 6059 OH: Thomas Shactman Interviews with Theodore W. Kheel 5776 AV: Theodore W. Kheel Interviews and Programs
Strikes and lockouts -- Newspapers; Strikes and lockouts -- Police; Strikes and lockouts -- Teachers; Strikes and lockouts -- New York (State) -- New York; Arbitration, Industrial; Industrial relations; Civil rights; Conflict management; Armed Forces; Kheel, Theodore Woodrow; American Foundation on Automation and Employment; Institute for Collective Bargaining and Group Relations; National Urban League; New York City Transit Authority; Pennsylvania State University
5758173
- Affinity Group Credit Cards (Box 1, Folder 1)
- American Foundation on Automation and Employment, 1962-1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- American Foundation on Automation and Employment, 1968-1973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- American Labor Movement, 1951-1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- American Labor Movement, 1970-1989 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Arbitrations - AAU-NCAA (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Arbitrations - Brewery Industry (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Arbitrations - Civil Rights (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Arbitrations - Entertainment Industry (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Arbitrations - Maritime (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Arbitrations - Milk Industry (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Arbitrations - Newspaper and Printing Industries (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Arbitrations - Pocketbook Workers Union - Leather Goods (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Arbitrations - Rubber Industry (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Arbitrations - Teamsters (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Arbitrations - Transit, 1953-1956 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Arbitrations - Transit, 1957-1963 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Arbitrations - Transit, 1965-1984 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Automation (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Automation House, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Automation House, 1971-1976 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Center for Non-Broadcast Television (Automation House) (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Christo's Gates Project (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Civil Rights - Kheel Articles, Speeches and Statements (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Civil Rights - Kheel Booklet and Book on Equal Employment Opportunity (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Civil Rights - New York and National Urban Leagues, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Civil Rights - National Urban League Civil Rights Bill, Equal Employment Opportunity Drive, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Civil Rights - National Urban League (Ghana, Airlines), 1957 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Civil Rights - National Urban League, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Civil Rights - National Urban League (African Student Airlift), 1960 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Civil Rights - Electrical Workers Union Apprentices, 1962-1964 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Civil Rights - Gandhi Society, 1962-1964 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Civil Rights - Alabama Libel Suits; Sullivan v. New York Times (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Civil Rights - President's Committee on Equal Employment Opportunity - Kheel Report, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Civil Rights - Mayor's Committee on Job Advancement (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Civil Rights - Apprenticeship Plan, Local' 6; International Typographical Union (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Civil Rights, 1968-1970 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Civil Rights - Minority Hiring by City of New York, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Columbia Univ. Campus (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Composers and Lyricists Guild v. Television and Movie Producers (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Conflict Resolution - General (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Conflict Resolution t. Attica (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Conflict Resolution - Board of Mediation of Community Disputes (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Conflict Resolution Institute Center) for Mediation and (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Conflict Resolution (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Electrical Industry (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Experiments in Art and Technology (Box 1, Folder 47)
- Clay Felker - New York Magazine and Village Voice (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Foundation on Employee Health, Medical Care and Welfare (Box 1, Folder 49)
- David Graiver (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Hospitals - Strikes (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Industrial and Labor Relations - Air Transport (Box 1, Folder 52)
- Industrial and Labor Relations - Alternatives to Strike, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  Scope and Contents
  Montly Labor Review, September
- Industrial and Labor Relations - Arbitration (Box 1, Folder 54)
- Industrial and Labor Relations - Schelling's Essay on Bargaining (Box 1, Folder 55)
- Industrial and Labor Relations - Collective Bargaining, 1946-1963 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- Industrial and Labor Relations - Collective Bargaining, 1964-1967 (Box 1, Folder 57)
- Industrial and Labor Relations - Collective Bargaining, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 58)
- Industrial and Labor Relations - Collective Bargaining, 1970-1980 (Box 1, Folder 59)
- Industrial and Labor Relations - Public Sector Bargaining (including Taylor Law), 1968 (Box 1, Folder 60)
- Industrial and Labor Relations - Public Sector Bargaining, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 61)
- Industrial and Labor Relations - Public Sector Bargaining, 1971-1993 (Box 1, Folder 62)
- Industrial and Labor Relations - Strikes (Box 1, Folder 63)
- Industrial and Labor Relations - Taylor Law (Kheel Report to Speaker Trivia) (Box 1, Folder 64)
- Institute-e for Collective Bargaining and Group Relations, 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 65)
- Institute for Collective Bargaining and Group Relations, 1970-1987 (Box 1, Folder 66)
- Kheel - Awards, Honors and Special Recognition, 1948-1965 (Box 1, Folder 67)
- Kheel - Awards, Honors and Special Recognition, 1966-1991 (Box 1, Folder 68)
- Kheel - Biographical Materials, 1943-1958 (Box 1, Folder 69)
- Kheel - Biographical Materials, 1959-1967 (Box 1, Folder 70)
- Kheel - Biographical Materials, 1968-1970 (Box 1, Folder 71)
- Kheel - Biographical Materials, 1971-1979 (Box 1, Folder 72)
- Kheel - Biographical Materials, 1980-1993 (Box 1, Folder 73)
- Kheel - Corporate Directorships, Offices and Investments (Box 1, Folder 74)
- Kheel - Favorable Media and Official Comment, 1947-1963 (Box 1, Folder 75)
- Kheel - Favorable Media and Official Comment, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 76)
- Kheel - Gilbane Housing Development in Panama (Box 1, Folder 77)
- Kheel - Litigation as Counsel (Box 1, Folder 78)
- Kheel - Litigation as Party (Box 1, Folder 79)
- Kheel's Relations with Media (Box 1, Folder 80)
- John V. Lindsay as Mayor (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Local 6, International Typographical Union (Box 2, Folder 2)
- MARC (Metropolitan Applied Research Center) (Box 2, Folder 3)
- MGM Proxy Fight (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Maritime Industry, 1957-1959 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Maritime Industry, 1962-1963 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Maritime Industry, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  August 10th-October16th
- Maritime Industry, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Maritime Industry, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  August 3rd-December23rd
- Maritime Industry, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Maritime Industry, 1966-1973 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Milk Driver Discutes and Strikes (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Municipal Government Service 1946-1947 (Non Transit) (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Municipal Government Service (Non-Transit), 1948 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  January-June
- Municipal Government Service (Non Transit) (Box 2, Folder 15)
  July-October
- Municipal Government Service (Non Transit) (Box 2, Folder 16)
  November 1st-15th
- Municipal Government Service (Non Transit) (Box 2, Folder 17)
  November 16th-December 27th
- Report of the Mayor's Transit Advisory Committee, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  September 9th
- Municipal Government Service (Transit), 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Municipal Government Service (Transit), 1948 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Municipal Government Service (Transit), 1948 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  July-December
- National Football League, 1968-1973 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- National Football League, 1974-1982 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- New York City and State Politics, 1946-1967 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- New York City and State Politics, 1968-1978 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- New York City and State Politics - Gubernatorial, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- New York City and State Politics - Mayoral; Kheel v. Koch, 1981-1989 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- New York City Development and Economic Data, 1947-1965 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- New York City Development and Economic Data, 1966-1979 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- New York City Development and Economic Data - Ehrenhalt Reports, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- New York Governmental Process and Structure and Kheel Articles (Box 2, Folder 31)
- New York City Private Transit (Buses) - Kheel as Impartial Chairman (Box 2, Folder 32)
- New York City Transit Authority and Transport Workers Union -Kheel as Impartial Arbitrator (Box 2, Folder 33)
- Kheel as Impartial Arbitrator Amalgamated-Queens, Nassau Lines (Box 2, Folder 34)
- New York City Transit - Mayors' Fact Finding and Mediation Boards (Box 2, Folder 35)
- New York City - Bus Strikes and Threats, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  June 6th-July 20th
- New York City - Bus Strikes and Threats, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  July 21st-November 29th
- New York City - Bus Strikes and Threats, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  May 25th-December 29th
- New York City - Bus Strikes and Threats, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  November
- New York City - Bus Strikes and Threats, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  December
- New York City - Bus Strikes and Threats, 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- New York City - Bus Strikes and Threats, 1954-1960 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- New York City - Subway and Bus Strikes and Threats, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- New York City - Subway and Bus Strikes and Threats, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- New York City - Subway and Bus Strikes and Threats, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- New York City - Subway and Bus Strikes and Threats, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- New York City - Subway and Bus Strike, 1965-1966 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- New York City - Subway and Bus Strike, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  January 6th-January 11th
- New York City - Subway and Bus Strike, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  January 12th-26th
- New York City - Subway and Bus Strikes and Threats, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 50)
- New York City - Subway and Bus Strikes and Threats, 1969-1971 (Box 2, Folder 51)
- New York City - Subway and Bus Strikes and Threats, 1973-1979 (Box 2, Folder 52)
- New York City - Subway and Bus Strikes and Threats, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 53)
- New York Metropolitan Transit Authority (Box 2, Folder 54)
- New York Magazine - Rupert Murdoch Controversy (Box 2, Folder 55)
- The New York Post - Gail '-Sheeny Profile of Dorothy Schiff (Box 2, Folder 56)
- The New York Times - Excerpt from The Kingdom and the Power (Box 2, Folder 57)
- Newspaper Disputes and Strikes, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Newspaper Disputes and Strikes, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  March 20th-June 27th
- Newspaper Disputes and Strikes, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  June 30th-September 18th
- Newspaper Disputes and Strikes, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  September 18th-September 24th
- Newspaper Disputes and Strikes, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  September 25th-October 9th
- Newspaper Disputes and Strikes, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  October 10th-November 16th
- Newspaper Disputes and Strikes, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Newspaper Disputes and Strikes, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  March 11th-April 1st
- Newspaper Disputes and Strikes, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  April 1st-April 30th
- Newspaper Disputes and Strikes, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  May 1st-November 6th
- Newspaper Disputes and Strikes, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Newspaper Disputes and Strikes, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  March 24th-April 20th
- Newspaper Disputes and Strikes, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  April 21st-May 27th
- Newspaper Disputes and Strikes, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  June 27th-November 10th
- Newspaper Disputes and Strikes, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Newspaper Disputes and Strikes, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Newspaper Disputes and Strikes, 1975-1977 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Newspaper Disputes and Strikes, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  September 1st-September 30th
- Newspaper Disputes and Strikes, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  October 2nd-October 31st
- Newspaper Disputes and Strikes; Possible Sale of New York Daily News, 1978-1982 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Newspaper Issues - Possible Sale of New York Daily News April 5 -May 25, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  April 5th-May 25th
- Newspaper Issues - Possible Sale of Amsterdam News, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Newspaper Issues - Sale of New York Post, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Newspaper Disputes and Strikes - New York Post, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  January 22nd-July31st
- Newspaper Disputes and Strikes - New York Post, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  August 2nd-November 20th
- Newspaper Disputes and Strikes - New York Post, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  November 20th-December 24th
- Newspaper Disputes and Strikes - New York Post, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- New York Daily News Strike - Kneel and Freeman Manuscript, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- New York Daily News Strike - Chronology of Key Events, 1990-1991 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- New York Daily News Strike and Sale, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 30)
- Pennsylvania State University Controversy (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Samuel R. Pierce, Jr. (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Plumbing Industry (Box 3, Folder 33)
- Police Disputes and Strikes (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Police Review Board, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Punta Cana Beach Resort (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Queens College Controversy (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Railroad Disputes and Strikes, 1964-1967 (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Railroad Disputes and Strikes, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Railroad Disputes and Strikes, 1980-1983 (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Republic National Bank (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Sanitation Workers Disputes and Strikes, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 42)
- P.L. "Roy" Siemiller (President International Association of Machinists and of American Foundation on Automation and Employment (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Stirling Homex Corp. (Box 3, Folder 44)
- Taxi Driver Disputes and Strikes (Box 3, Folder 45)
- Teachers Disputes and Strikes, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 46)
- Teachers Disputes and Strikes, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 47)
- Teachers Disputes and Strikes, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 48)
- Teachers Disputes and Strikes, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 49)
- Teachers Disputes and Strikes - Ocean Hill-Brownsville, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 50)
- Teachers Disputes and Strikes, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 51)
- Teachers Disputes and Strikes, 1970-1975 (Box 3, Folder 52)
- Transit Fares (incl. Kheel articles, speeches, statements), 1955-1963 (Box 3, Folder 53)
- Transit Fares and Tolls, 1965-1968 (Box 3, Folder 54)
- Transit Fares and Tolls, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 55)
- Transit Fares and Tolls, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 56)
- Transit Fares and Tolls, 1971-1973 (Box 3, Folder 57)
- Transit Fares and Tolls, 1974-1978 (Box 3, Folder 58)
- Transport Workers Union (Box 3, Folder 59)
- Transportation Bond Issue, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 60)
- Transportation Bond Issue; Railroad Preservation Bond Issue, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 61)
- Transportation Policy (incl. TWK articles and statements), 1955-1957 (Box 3, Folder 62)
- Transportation Policy (incl. TWK articles and statements), 1958 (Box 3, Folder 63)
- Transportation Policy, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 64)
- Transportation Policy - Port of New York Authority, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 65)
- Transportation Policy - Port of New York Authority, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 66)
- Transportation Policy - Port of New York Authority, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 67)
- Transportation Policy - Port of New York Authority, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 68)
- Transportation Policy - Port of New York Authority - Covenant; Rutgers Law Review article, 1962-1973 (Box 3, Folder 69)
- Transportation Policy - Port of New York Authority, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 70)
- Transportation Policy - Port of New York Authority, 1974-1981 (Box 3, Folder 71)
- United Nations (Box 3, Folder 72)